人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译 Silmar
翻译 尼克白
翻译 送小孩
翻译  树树
翻译  泰斯
校对  泰斯·雪诺
校对  Silmar
时间轴 加森
时间轴 全家幸福筒
时间轴 imok
时间轴 崽猪
特效/后期 鱼骨头
特效/后期 拉图
顾问 屈畅(ccxx)
总监 泰斯·雪诺
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
第四季 第九集
她什么样
What was she like?
她
She...
有一头红发
she had red hair.
是吗
Oh?
-她脚多大  -你想说什么
- How big were her feet? - What do you want me to say?
我想让你告诉我  拥有另一半是什么感觉
I want you to tell me what it was like to have someone.
有个人和你一起
To be with someone.
你爱着她  她也爱着你
To love someone and have them love you back.
我们死期将至  比我预想早太多
We're all gonna die a lot sooner than I'd planned.
我想明白那感觉也只好问你了
You're the closest I'll ever get to knowing.
你跟吉莉没试过
So you and Gilly never?
没
No.
她刚生了孩子
She just had a baby.
她也没主动提过
And she never offered.
如果她主动了
But if she had,
你会吗
you would have?
你会打破誓言吗
You'd have broken your vows?
有趣的是
The interesting thing is,
我们的誓言也没明确禁止
our vows never specifically forbid
与女人发生亲密关系
intimate relations with women.
什么
What?
"我将不娶妻"  没错
"I shall take no wife," Yes,
誓言里说了  不可否认
that's in there. There's no denying that.
"不生子"  也很明确
"I shall father no children." It's very specific.
但我们的誓言对其它行为是否有所约束
But what do our vows have to say about other...
就见仁见智了
activities is open to interpretation.
我看艾里沙爵士可不管什么见仁见智
I don't think Ser Alliser cares much for interpretation.
反正他也没得见
Anyway, there's nothing for him to interpret.
我们啥都没做
We didn't.
到底什么感觉
So what's it like?
就是...
It's...
就是有个人  完完全全的另一个人
there's this person, this whole other person.
你满心满眼都是她  她满心满眼都是你
And you're wrapped up in them and they're wrapped up in you.
然后你
And you--
有那么一...
for a little--
一瞬间  你不仅仅是你自己
for a little while, you're more than just you.
你就...我说不清  我他妈又不是诗人
You're-- I don't know. I'm not a bleeding poet.
嗯  你真不是
No, you're really not.
瞧我得到了什么
What did I get for it?
差六吋一箭穿心
An arrow six inches from my heart.
我猜我们挨个当箭靶的日子也不远了
There'll be arrows for all of us soon, I imagine.
会来的
There will.
他们已经让我遭遇了最可怕的事情
They've already done the worst thing to me they could ever do.
去睡一会儿吧  山姆
Go get some sleep, Sam.
这一班我来守
I'll take this watch.
我有没有给你们讲过她
Did I ever tell you about her?
-我的雪拉  -讲过
- My Sheila? - Yes.
那可是难忘的一夜
That was a night to remember.
当然我是喝得有点儿多
Of course, I'd had a good bit to drink.
她的獠牙很锋利
Her fangs were sharp,
可她晓得怎么用
but she knew how to use them.
她下面又甜又软
And she was nice and soft down below.
不  她可不是普通的野兽
No, she was no ordinary beast.
多少男人...
Many is the man who--
我知道你没操过熊
I know you never fucked a bear.
你也知道自己没操过熊
You know you never fucked a bear.
我现下不想琢磨你没操过的那头熊
Right now I don't want to think about the bear you never fucked.
我现下只想琢磨
Right now all I want to think about
这里的每一支箭  都要穿过一只乌鸦的心
is each one of these arrows finding its way into a crow's heart.
我们可能还要等些时候呢
We could be waiting here a while.
那很好
Good.
我们等得越久  我的箭就越多
The longer we wait, the more arrows I'll have.
他们来到我们的土地上
They came up here to our land
建起高墙  说这是他们的地盘
and put up a big wall and said it was theirs.
然后把我们赶尽杀绝
Then they started hunting us down.
这次换成我们来杀他们
This time, we're the ones doing the hunting.
打打杀杀的事  你的话还真多
You've got a lot to say about killing.
话比箭还多
Even more words than arrows.
在那些村子里头  我杀的人可不比你少
Back in those villages, I killed just as many of them as you did.
只怕比你还多
More, I reckon.
是啊  可里面没有你那乌鸦情人
Yes, but none of those were your crow lover.
他可能已经死在我手里了
I probably killed him already.
这话你说过
So you've said.
就算没死
And if not,
他唯一的遗骸
the only thing left of him
也只会是挂在我脖子上的小玩意儿
is gonna be his fun bits hanging around my neck.
又在说嘴
More words.
知道我觉得你再见他会怎样吗
Know what I think you do when you see him?
用你那红毛小穴好好招待他
Serve him up a nice juicy slice of ginger minge.
你惦记那红毛小穴了吗
You been thinking about that ginger minge?
想知道是什么滋味
Wondering what it tasts like.
也许我想了
Maybe I have.
琼恩·雪诺是我的
Jon Snow is mine.
谁胆敢杀他
Anyone else tries to kill him,
我就送支箭给谁
I'll have an arrow for them.
你那些光头朋友太慢  拦不住我
And not one of your bald friends is fast enough to stop me.
什么要紧事不能等到明早呢  塔利
And what is it that couldn't wait until morning, Tarly?
伊蒙师傅
Maester Aemon.
-您怎么知道...  -知道是你吗
- How did you know-- - That it was you?
除了山姆威尔·塔利
Who else but Samwell Tarly
还有谁会浪费蜡烛
would be wasting candles
大半夜跑来读书呢
to read in the middle of the night?
-我来帮您  -噢  用不着
- Let me help you. - Oh, no need.
整个黑城堡我最熟悉的
I know my way around this library
就数这间图书室了
better than any other place in Castle Black.
数千书册
Thousands of books
却没有眼睛读
and no eyes to read them.
人到暮年  别的好处没有
Old age is a wonderful source of ironies
生活的讽刺倒是俯首可拾
if nothing else.
你还没回答我的问题
But you didn't answer my question.
你在读什么
What are you reading?
福尔学士的著作
Maester Faull.
啊  写野人的
Ah, the wildlings.
我可以担保  福尔学士终其一生
I can assure you that the closest Maester Faull
与野人的接触仅限于书卷
ever got to a wildling was this very library.
但书中所述的野人行径
But what he says about what they do,
全是事实
it's all true.
是遭遇野人的幸存者的实录
It's exactly what the survivors of their raids report.
是啊  想象一下野人会怎么讲我们
Yes, imagine the stories wildlings tell about us.
情爱是责任的大忌
Love is the death of duty.
我对你的朋友琼恩·雪诺说过一次
I told that to your friend Jon Snow once.
他没听  你也一样
He didn't listen and neither did you.
所以你没在长城上头守夜
Which is why you've abandoned your watch atop the Wall
却跑来读这些可怕的故事
to come here and read about the terrible things
忧心它们或许已经发生在你爱的姑娘身上
that may have happened to the girl you love.
我不爱她
I don't love her.
-你爱她  -不爱
- Yes, you do. - No.
你就是爱她
Yes, you do.
你第一次带她来见我  我就听出来了
Heard it in your voice when you first brought her to me.
我还记得情有所衷的语调
I remember how it sounds.
我也爱过
I was in love once.
是吗
You were?
你可以想象那可怜的姑娘
You can imagine all manner of horrors
和她的孩子遭遇各种各样的坏事
befalling that poor girl and her child.
想象一个糟老头子也曾和你一样
Is it so difficult to imagine that an old person was once,
青春年少  有那么难吗
more or less, like you?
对不起  学士
I'm sorry, Maester.
我不是那个意思
I didn't mean it like that.
你知道我来这里之前的身份吗
Do you know who I was before I came here?
只要我说出那个字  我会成为什么人吗
What I could have been if I'd only said the word?
你当然知道
Of course you do.
我还是伊蒙·坦格利安时  见过许多姑娘
I met many girls when I was Aemon Targaryen.
王位继承人总是这样
A future king always does.
其中一些特别主动
Some of them were quite forward
想要博得我的青睐
in their attempts to win my affections.
有一个成功了
One of them succeeded.
我当时真年轻啊
I was very young.
她是谁
Who was she?
我可以给你讲她的一切
I could tell you everything about her.
她是谁
Who she was,
我们如何初见
how we met,
她眼睛的颜色
the color of her eyes,
她鼻子的形状
and the shape of her nose.
我可以看到她
I can see her
就在我面前
right in front of me.
比你更真实
She's more real than you are.
我们可以讲一整晚那些年逝去的爱情
We could spend all night trading tales of lost loves.
死亡迫在眉睫
Nothing makes the past a sweeter place to visit
更显得回忆如此甜蜜
than the prospect of imminent death.
去睡觉  塔利
Go to bed, Tarly.
对不起  任何人不得进门  这是命令
Sorry, I can't open the gate for anybody. Orders.
你不明白  他们杀死了所有人
You don't understand. They killed everyone.
只剩下我和孩子
Everyone but me and my baby.
他们就在外面  我来的路上看见他们了
They're out there. I saw them on my way here.
他们可能看见我了  可能跟着我  求你了
They may have seen me. They may have followed me. Please.
对不起  我不能开
I'm sorry, I can't.
要是他们在外面发现我  你不知道...
If they find us out here, you don't know...
派普  快开门
Pyp! Open the gate.
-不行  -山姆  是你吗
- I can't. - Sam, is that you?
是我
Yes.
索恩严令不得开门
Thorne gave me strict orders to not open the gate.
派普  你他妈的给我开门
Oh, Pyp, open the fucking gate!
我从没听过你说脏话
I never heard you curse before.
是的  你最好习惯一下
Yes, well, best get used to it.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
你没事了
Shh, you're all right.
你当然没事了  勇敢的小伙子
Of course you are, my brave little fella.
-太可怕了  -对不起
- It was horrible. - I'm so, so sorry.
我回来后才知道的
I didn't know until I got back.
别让他们赶我走了  山姆
Don't let them send me away, Sam.
-永远不会  -我知道这里不留女人
- Never. - I know there's no women allowed.
谁敢赶你走  先要过我这一关
Anyone who tries to throw you out will be having words with me.
从现在开始  你去哪里
From now on, wherever you go,
我也去哪里
I go, too.
准备好
Get ready!
-守住门  -备战
- Man the gate! - Ready yourselves!
动作快
Make haste!
-备战  -上长城
- Prepare! - Up on the Wall!
快点  上去
Quickly! Up! Up!
那边有多少人
How many? How many are there?
在树林那边
Beyond the trees!
时候到了
It's time.
点火  全点上
Light them up! Light them all!
让开
Move!
动作快点
Pick up the pace!
快啊
Come on, come on.
好了  伙计们  第一桶
Here we go, boys, there's one.
来吧  第二桶
Let's go. There's two.
我们去搬下一批
Let's get the next load.
这是最后一桶油了  艾里沙爵士
That's the last of the oil, Ser Alliser.
你说有十万大军
100,000 you say?
是的  爵士
Yes, Ser.
你想说就说吧
You can say it if you like.
我们早该封锁隧道
We should have sealed the tunnel while we had the chance,
听你的建议
like you suggested.
那是个两难的决定  爵士
It was a difficult decision either way, Ser.
你知道管事意味着什么吗  雪诺大人
Do you know what leadership means, Lord Snow?
意味着每个长了嘴的聪明鬼
It means that the person in charge gets second-guessed
都可以质疑管事的人
by every clever little twat with a mouth.
但如果他也质疑自己
But if he starts second-guessing himself,
那就完了
that's the end--
他完了  聪明鬼完了
for him, for the clever little twats,
所有人都完了
for everyone.
这次不算完  完蛋的不是我们
This is not the end. Not for us.
只要你们尽忠职守
Not if you lot do your duty
坚持到击退他们就行
for however long it takes to beat them back.
然后你可以接着恨我
And then you get to go on hating me
我也可以接着讨厌你
and I get to go on wishing
怪你的野人婊子当初没干掉你
your wildling whore had finished the job.
你在这里很安全
You'll be safe down here.
我会尽快来看你
I'll check on you as soon as I can.
你又要离开我
You're leaving me again?
我不是离开你
I'm not leaving you.
你要去上面
You're going up there and
我们留在下面  这就是离开
we're staying down here. That's leaving.
你说过从今往后我们不分开
You said from now on we'd stay together.
我不是说在同一间屋子里
I didn't mean in the same room.
你要去外面做什么
What are you going to do out there?
-帮我的兄弟们  -怎么帮
- Help my brothers. - How?
你要和那些自由民打仗吗
You're going to fight the free folk when they come?
他们会杀了你  他们杀了鼹鼠村的所有人
They'll kill you. In Mole's Town, they killed everyone.
我不能和你躲在这里  让他们在外面打仗
I can't just hide here with you while they're fighting out there.
为什么不行  上面又不需要你
Why not? You won't matter up there.
这儿需要你
You will down here.
我是守夜人的汉子  吉莉
I am a man of the Night's Watch, Gilly.
我发誓保卫长城
I made a promise to defend the Wall
我必须遵守誓言
and I have to keep it
男子汉就该这样
because that's what men do.
向我保证你不会死
Promise me you won't die.
我保证我不会死
I promise you I won't die.
长城那边的野人比这边要多得多
There's a lot more wildlings on the other side of the Wall than this side.
我们有很多武器和装备
We've got loads of weapons and things.
这里对我们来说再好不过了
It's the perfect place for us to be.
我从没掷过长矛
I've never thrown a spear before.
我从没握过开刃的剑
I've never held a sword with a proper edge.
这地方真不是我该来的
This is no place for me to be.
你不怕吗
You're not afraid?
我当然怕了
Of course I'm afraid.
有一帮野人要来杀我们
There's a band of wildlings coming to kill us.
你要是连一帮野人都怕
If you're afraid of a band of wildlings,
那你之前到底是怎么干掉异鬼的
how in seven hells did you manage to kill a white walker?
我那时候不知道自己能杀死它
I didn't know I was going to kill it.
但我总得做点什么
But I had to do something.
我别无选择
I didn't have any choice.
不然它就会杀死吉莉  掳走孩子
It was going to kill Gilly and take the baby.
如果那时候有人问我的名字
If someone had asked me my name right then,
我肯定答不上来
I wouldn't have known.
我不再是山姆威尔·塔利
I wasn't Samwell Tarly anymore.
也不是守夜人的事务官
I wasn't a steward in the Night's Watch
或者蓝道·塔利之子  或者别的什么身份
or son of Randyll Tarly or any of that.
我什么都不是
I was nothing at all.
而你什么都不是的时候
And when you're nothing at all,
就没什么好怕的了
there's no more reason to be afraid.
但你现在又害怕了
But you're afraid now?
是的
Yes, well...
我现在又有身份了
I'm not nothing anymore.
他们大多上了长城
Most of their men are up top.
下面只剩不到二十人
Didn't count more than 20 down here. Leftovers.
前门由一个大胖子和一个小瘦子看守
They got a big fat one and a little bony one manning the front.
城墙有多高
How high are the walls?
估计等我们翻过去了  他们才会察觉
Well, we'll be up and over before they know what's happened.
杀乌鸦去
Let's kill some crows!
出发
Come on!
快点  兄弟们
Come on, brothers!
弓手  上弦
Archers nock.
其他人待命
Everyone else hold.
不
No!
我说上弦  待命  你们这些蠢货
I said nock and hold, you cunts!
-上弦是要你们拉弓吗  -不是  爵士
- Does nock mean draw? - No, Ser!
-待命是要你们扔桶吗  -不是  爵士
- Does fucking hold mean fucking drop? - No, Ser!
-你们打算今晚死在这儿吗  -不  爵士
- You all plan to die here tonight? - No, Ser!
答得好  拉弓
That's very good to hear. Draw!
不是我  在下面
No, down below!
拉弓  烧死他们
Draw! Light them up.
快  起来
Come on, get up!
他们在攻打南门
They're attacking the southern gate!
-现在吗  -是的
- Now? - Now.
我下去看看  史林特兄弟  长城是你的了
I'm going down there. Brother Slynt, you have the Wall.
什么
What?
你们还傻站着干什么  给我放箭
What are you fucking waiting for? Loose!
你们听到了  放
You heard the man. Loose!
你去那边
You, over there.
-射中了吗  -没有
- Did you get one? - No.
该死  派普  该死
Ah, shit, Pyp! Shit.
-山姆  -怎么了
- Sam. - Yeah?
我们可能要死了
I think we're gonna die.
如果你老是射偏  我们当然会死
If you keep missing, we will.
快爬
Come on!
兄弟们
Brothers!
上百代守夜人保卫过这座城堡
100 generations have defended this castle.
从未失陷
She's never fallen before.
今夜也不会失守
She will not fall tonight.
爬上城墙的是瑟恩人
Those are Thenns at our walls.
他们会吃掉自己的手下败将
They eat the flesh of the men they kill.
你们想当瑟恩人的晚餐吗
Do you want to fill the belly of a Thenn tonight?
不
No!
今夜  我们血战到底
Tonight we fight.
等到旭日东升  我向你们保证
And when the sun rises, I promise you,
黑城堡将屹立不倒
Castle Black will stand!
守夜人将万世长存
The Night's Watch will stand.
剑在手  跟我走
With me now! Now with me!
没有军纪  也没有经过训练
No discipline. No training.
不过是帮乌合之众
Gang of thieves, that's all this is.
我指挥过君临的都城守备队
I commanded the City Watch of King's Landing.
他们会绝对服从命令
Those men obeyed orders.
我们不能眼睁睁看着他们攻打城门
We can't just let them attack the gate.
城门上的铁栅粗达四吋  全是精钢打造
The bars of those gates are four inches of cold-rolled steel.
城下可是骑着长毛象的巨人
Those are giants riding mammoths down there!
你觉得光靠精钢铁栅就能挡住他们吗
Do you think your cold-rolled steel is gonna stop them?
哪儿有什么巨人
No such thing as giants.
那都是骗小孩的故事
A story for the children.
史林特兄弟
Brother Slynt.
我们刚得到消息  艾里沙爵士需要您去支援
We just got word that Ser Alliser needs you below.
您现在是最有经验的人  爵士  他需要您
You're the most experienced man he's got, Ser, and he needs you.
要我下去
Needed below?
好  很好
Yes. Yes.
弓手  上弦
Archers, nock your arrows!
上弦
Nock arrows!
拉弓
Draw!
射
Loose!
他们黎明前登不上顶
They won't summit before dawn.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
因为我登过
Because I've made that climb.
我想他们要比你那会儿心急得多
I think they're in a bigger hurry than you were.
守住桥
Hold the bridge!
抓紧  稳住
Hold, wait for it!
快扔石头
Come on with the rocks!
上弦
Nock!
拉弓
Draw!
射
Loose!
趴下
Down!
不  不要
No! No!
去城门  快点动起来
To the gate. Come on, let's move.
门要被打开了
It's gonna open.
我射死一个  一箭穿心
I got one right through the heart. He's dead.
-杀光了吗  -没有
- Oh, is it over? - No.
那好吧
Well, then...
没事的  你不会有事
You're all right. You're all right.
我去找人帮忙
I'll get help.
伊蒙学士马上就到
Maester Aemon is coming.
他会有办法的
He's gonna make it all right.
-丢  -丢
- Now. - Now!
外门保不住了
The outer gate won't hold.
带上五个人  守住内门
Take five men, hold the inner gate.
是
Aye.
守住门
Hold the gate.
如果他们进来了...
If they make it through...
他们进不来
They won't.
跟我走  希尔  还有你  库珀
Come on, Hill. And you, Cooper.
你们仨  跟我来
You three, on me.
快点  你们这些懒鬼
Come on, you lazy bastards.
撒油
Oil.
给坡道上撒油
Oil on the ramp!
保护城门
Protect the gate!
把他抬进去
Get him inside.
一定要给我守住门
Hold the fucking gate!
守住
Hold it!
下面需要支援
We need more men down here.
-我们必须守住门  -但这里也需要人
- We have to hold the gate. - But we need men here.
跟琼恩说  他现在是头儿
Tell Jon. He's in command.
我们走
Let's go.
把我送上去  听见没有
Get me to the top! You hear me?!
你叫奥利  是吗
Your name's Olly, right?
听我说  奥利  把我送上去
Listen to me, Olly. Get me to the top.
等我们发出信号后  再把我们放下来
And when we give the signal, bring us back down.
听到没
You hear me?
找个武器跟他们战斗  奥利
Find a weapon, Olly. Fight them.
都让开  我们走
Clear the way! Let's go!
-别挡道  -都让开
- Out of the way! - Get out of here!
切断绳子
Cut the rope!
-别  -不
- Wait! - No!
-再多来几个弓箭手  -我来
- We need more archers. - Here I am.
-快点  -快
- Come on. - Quickly.
你来做什么
What are you doing up here?
野人杀过城墙了
The wildlings are over the walls.
艾里沙爵士已经倒下
Ser Alliser's fallen.
城堡坚持不了多久
The castle won't stand much longer.
艾迪  长城是你的了
Edd, you have the Wall.
如果他们再使长毛象  就用火烧他们
If they try the mammoths again, drop fire on them.
如果那些人爬得太高  就放巨镰
If the climbers get too high, drop the scythe on them.
来  兄弟们  跟我一起战斗
Come, brothers. Now fight with me!
咱们享受最后一晚  是吧  伙计们
Might as well enjoy our last night, right, boys?
把他妈的箭都点上火
Light the fuckers up!
上弦  拉弓
Nock! Draw!
射
Loose!
我们怎么挡住那家伙
How are we gonna stop that?
已经射他二十箭了
Shot 20 arrows in him already.
你听见琼恩的话了  我们要守住门
You heard Jon. We hold the gate.
琼恩·雪诺不是总司令
Jon Snow's not Lord Commander.
我们要守住门
We hold the gate!
圣母  救我  天父  救我
Mother, save me. Father, save me.
这儿没有神
The gods aren't down here.
只有我们六个  听见没
It's the six of us. You hear me?
长夜将至  我从今开始守望
Night gathers and now my watch begins.
至死方休
It shall not end until my death.
我将不娶妻  不封地
I shall take no wife, hold no lands,
不生子
father no children.
我将不戴宝冠  不争荣宠
I shall wear no crown and win no glory.
我将尽忠职守  生死于斯
I shall live and die at my post.
我是黑暗中的利剑
I am the sword in the darkness.
长城上的守卫
I am the watcher on the walls.
守卫王国的坚盾
I am the shield that guards the realms of men.
我将生命与荣耀献给守夜人
I pledge my life and honor to the Night's Watch
今夜如此  夜夜皆然
for this night and all the nights to come!
我不希望你出去
I don't want you out there.
你不能永远保护我
You can't protect me forever.
一旦城堡沦陷  也无处可藏
There won't be anywhere to hide if the castle falls.
比起你  我更需要它
I need him more than I need you.
我们需要你  小子
We need you, boy.
琼恩·雪诺
Jon Snow.
嘘  别说话
Hush. Don't talk.
还记得那个山洞吗
Do you remember the cave?
我们不该离开那山洞
We should have stayed in the cave.
我们回山洞去
We'll go back there.
你什么都不懂  琼恩·雪诺
You know nothing, Jon Snow.
放巨镰  兄弟们
Drop the scythe, boys!
-拉起来  -拉起来
- Hoist her up. - Hoist her up!
今晚够他们受的了
They've had enough for one night.
别欢呼太大声
Don't cheer too loud.
他们的人数依然是我们的一千倍
They still outnumber us 1,000 to one.
托蒙德
Tormund.
结束了
It's over.
放弃吧
Let it end.
真汉子就该这样结束
This is how a man ends.
把他锁起来
Put him in chains.
我们晚点再问他话
We'll question him later.
我应该把你
I should have thrown you
从长城顶上扔下去  臭小子
from the top of the Wall, boy!
是啊
Aye.
真该这样
You should have.
啊  是我  是我啊
Whoa, it's me. It's me.
我答应过你  不是吗
I promised you, didn't I?
我们挡住了他们
We held them off.
一晚而已
For one night.
这是伟大的胜利
This is a great victory.
伟大的胜利
A great victory?
曼斯在试探我们的防御  他差点就攻破了
Mance was testing our defenses. He almost made it through.
他还有更多的巨人  更多的长毛象
And he has more giants. He has more mammoths.
还有千倍于我们的人
He has 1,000 times as many men.
他们今晚还会进攻
They'll hit us again tonight.
也许我们能抵挡他们一两天
Maybe we can hold them off for a day or two,
但绝无可能击败他们
but we'll never beat them.
你要去哪里
Where are we going?
去找曼斯
Going to find Mance.
去找...你不能去
To fi--- you can't do that.
没人给你下令
No one gave you any orders.
还有谁能下令
Who's left to give orders?
野人之所以组建成军  全因为曼斯
The wildling army's only an army because of Mance.
他联合了上百个战斗部落
He united 100 warring tribes.
没了曼斯  他们群龙无首
Without Mance, they lose their leader.
没了目标  就会彼此开战
They lose their purpose. They go back to fighting each other.
四散回家
Scatter back to their homes.
没了曼斯
Without Mance?
你要去杀死他吗
You're going to kill him?
我去试试
I'm gonna try.
你根本没法靠近他一百码之内
They'll never let you within 100 yards of him.
就算你过去了  就算你杀了他
And even if they did, even if you managed to kill him--
他们会杀我吗  我不去  他们也会杀死我
They'll kill me? If I don't go, they'll kill me anyway.
把我们剩下的人全杀了
They'll kill the rest of us, too.
他们不会直接杀死你
They won't just kill you.
他们会烹了你  活剐了你
They'll boil you. They'll flay you.
让你生不如死
They'll make it last days.
你说得对  这个计划真烂
You're right. It's a bad plan.
你有什么计划
What's your plan?
他们守住了大门
They held the gate.
带几个兄弟下来帮你
Get some brothers down here to help you.
我们必须烧掉尸体
We need to burn the bodies.
升起外门
Raise the outer gate.
我一出去就立刻放下来
Then lower it again as soon as I'm out.
你干什么
What are you doing?
我答应过莫尔蒙  不会再丢掉它
I promised Mormont I'd never lose it again.
万一我这次不能回来
In case I don't come back.
琼恩
Jon.
你要回来
Come back.